Guide to the Washington Square College Evening News RG.39.191
New York University Archives
Washington Square College Evening News
1933-1967
New York University Archives
RG.39.191
5.5 Linear Feet in 3 flat boxes and 3 reels of microfilm
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Washington Square College Evening News dating from 1933 to 1967. This newspaper documents local and national news, campus living, student clubs, and student life at NYU as it pertained to the Evening Division of students. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collection includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Some issues are bound.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Newspapers are arranged in chronological order.
Biographical / Historical
New York University has had many student newspapers with many different names since its founding. The Heights campus and the Washington Square campus had separate student newspapers until 1973 when the Heights campus was closed. The Evening Division was the designation for students who took night classes at Washington Square College. The newspaper ran from 1933 to 1935 and again from 1943 to 1967.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must consult microfilm copies when possible due to the fragility of the original newspapers.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of student newspaper the Washington Square College Evening News, dating from 1933 to 1967. The newspaper was printed daily and documented student life, university news, and local or international news with relevancy to NYU's Evening Division. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collection includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Some issues are bound.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Student activities.; College student newspapers and periodicals.
- Microfilm copies
  - Washington Square College Evening News, 1933 (Box Microfilm 5, Reel 5101)
  - Washington Square College Evening News, 1937-1953 (Box Microfilm 5, Reel 5102)
  - Washington Square College Evening News, 1953-1967 (Box Microfilm 5, Reel 5103)
- Print copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Evening News, March 28, 1933-May 10, 1967 (Box 1)
- Bound print copies (restricted due to preservation concerns)
  - Washington Square College Evening News, October 1933-May 1935 (Box 2)
  - Washington Square College Evening News, November 1936-April 1938 (Box Shared University Archives 080)
  - Washington Square College Evening News, September 1940-May 1941 (Box 2)